roomsforafrica.com 2019-10-25

# Privacy Policy - RoomsForAfrica

RoomsForAfrica respects your privacy and we have created this privacy statement to demonstrate that commitment. All the information obtained through the RoomsForAfrica website ("Our Website") is treated as confidential. We request Information from you to fulfil our reservation services, to make your visit more productive and to provide you with a better service. 

Our Privacy policy explains some of the questions you may have in this regard: 

  1. ##  What personal information does RoomsForAfrica gather and how is this information used? 

You are not required to provide RoomsForAfrica with any personal information unless and until you choose to make an accommodation enquiry, online booking or sign up for one of our other services. The information we gather from our customers helps us continually improve our service to you. The types of information we gather include: 

    * ##  Information you give us 

We store any information you enter on Our Website or give us in any other way. The majority of this information is required for us to fulfil your accommodation enquiries, bookings and in communications with you. You can choose not to provide us with additional information, but then you might not be able to take full advantage of many of the features on Our Website. 

    * ##  User interaction information 

To help provide a better service, we usually monitor the usefulness and effectiveness of our website and communications with you. This includes identifying which newsletters were more popular, which articles were read and which portions of our website are well received and which could be improved. 

    * ##  Information from other sources 

We may receive information about you from other affiliated entities and add it to our account information. For example these might include credit card agencies, courier services or accommodation providers which help us to fulfil current and future reservations and prevent fraud. 

    * ##  Automatic Information 

In addition to the information which you may volunteer to us, certain Information is automatically collected whenever you interact with Our Website. For example we collect technical information such as operating system and browser type and version, which we use to ensure that Our Website caters for the technical needs of our users. 

  2. ##  How does RoomsForAfrica use IP Data and Cookies? 

    * ##  IP Data 

When you enter Our Website, we collect your IP address, which identifies your Internet Service Provider, but does not identify you as an individual. This information is used for the operation of Our Website, and to maintain the quality of the service. Additionally, this information is used for general statistical purposes regarding the use of RoomsForAfrica. 

    * ##  Cookies 

Cookies are small elements of data stored on your computer's hard drive or memory by your browser when you visit Our Website. Each cookie contains unique characteristics so that our web server can later recognize your computer. We use cookies to make reserving accommodation faster and easier. Some of the features of Our Website may not work properly or not at all if you disable the use of cookies. The information collected by cookies placed by us is anonymous and does not contain your personal Information. 

  3. ##  With whom does RoomsForAfrica share the information it receives? 

Information about our customers is an important part of our business, and we are not in the business of selling it to other companies. We will share customer information only as described below and with members of our own group, which share similar privacy policies. 

    * ##  Accommodation providers 

RoomsForAfrica gives limited access to your personal information to the accommodation providers with whom you have chosen to enquire at or make a reservation. We only give access to that portion of your personal information that is needed by the establishment to respond to your enquiry and/or process your reservation. Accommodation providers view your details on their membership area of ResAfrica.com (ResAfrica is part of the RoomsForAfrica group). The ResAfrica.com website is a secure website and is protected using Secure Socket Layer (SSL). SSL is the globally accepted standard technology used to encrypt your information during transmission. 

    * ##  Third-party reservation partners 

We make use of and integrate with third-party companies to obtain up-to-the-minute availability for some of the establishments listed on Our Websites. We further use these companies to process reservations for these establishments. These partner companies will have limited access to your personal information and only that portion required to process your reservation. They will not have access to your credit card information. 

    * ###  Third-party service providers 

We may employ or use other companies and individuals to perform functions our behalf. This will require them having access to personal information needed to perform their functions. The information we provide to such third parties is confidentiality and to be used solely for the purpose for which it has been provided. 

    * ##  Business restructuring 

We may need to restructure our business operations by selling one or more of our businesses, or part of a business. In such transactions, we may transfer your personal Information to a third party as a part of such merger, acquisition, reorganization, or sale. If this is the case, we will make you aware of these changes. 

    * ##  As required by laws and regulations 

We may disclose account or other personal Information to third parties when we believe it is necessary to enforce or comply with relevant laws, orders or regulations, our terms and conditions, our rights, contractual agreements, property and safety of our staff or users and in protection against fraudulent activities on Our Website. 

    * ##  With Your Consent 

Other than as set out above, we will not sell, rent or trade your personal information to third parties for marketing purposes without your consent and you will have an opportunity to choose not to share your information. 

  4. ##  What does RoomsForAfrica do to protect the information it receives? 

Our Website has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of all information under our control. Your credit card information is only transacted on a secure server and is never emailed. This secure server is protected using Secure Socket Layer (SSL). SSL is the globally accepted standard technology used to encrypt your information during transmission. Credit card details are not stored on Our Website and are deleted once reservations have been processed. 

  5. ##  What about links to third party websites? 

Some pages on Our Website include functionality from, and links to, third party websites such as Google Maps, FaceBook and Twitter. These websites are governed by their own privacy statements, and we are not responsible for their operations, including but not limited to their processing of personal information. We advise you to review their privacy statements before providing them with your personal information. 

  6. ##  How does RoomsForAfrica communicate with me? 

We use the information you give us to facilitate accommodation and other travel related services. This will necessitate our communicating with you in this regard. Our preferred means of communication with you is via email, using the email address you have provided us with. Alternatively, should the need arise, such as for last minute bookings, we will contact you telephonically, using the telephone number you have provided us with. 

We may further communicate with you in general, to respond to your queries, to notify you about special offers that may be of interest to you, to customize your experience of Our Website, assist you, resolve disputes and other communications in the normal course of operating Our Website. Newsletters and special offerings make it easy for you to take advantage of special opportunities on Our Website. We hope you will find these emails interesting and informative. You will have the opportunity to choose not to receive these emails in any such email we send. We only want to communicate with you if you want to hear from us. 

##  Revisions to this privacy policy 

If you have any questions about this privacy statement or the practices of the RoomsForAfrica website, please contact us and we will try to resolve them. Please note that we may review our Privacy Policy from time to time, and we may make periodic changes to this policy. We will notify you about material changes to this Privacy Policy by sending an email to the address you provided us with or by placing notice on our website. Therefore, you may wish to bookmark this page and/or periodically review this page to see recent changes. 

As always should you wish to terminate your account with RoomsForAfrica or update your privacy or user preferences you will be able to do so by following the relevant links on email we send you. 

Thank you for reading our Privacy Notice.
